<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ciml.sdsc.edu//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://ciml.sdsc.edu//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2025-02-06T02:26:29+00:00</updated><id>https://ciml.sdsc.edu//feed.xml</id><title type="html">CIML</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">SDSC CIML 2022 Summer Institute</title><link href="https://ciml.sdsc.edu//blog/2022/Summer-Inst/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SDSC CIML 2022 Summer Institute" /><published>2022-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ciml.sdsc.edu//blog/2022/Summer-Inst</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ciml.sdsc.edu//blog/2022/Summer-Inst/"><![CDATA[<h3>SDSC's Cyberinfrastructure-Enabled Machine Learning Summer Institute</h3>
<p>The San Diego Supercomputer Center (SDSC) Cyberinfrastructure-Enabled Machine Learning (CIML) project is focused on teaching researchers and students the best-known practices for effectively running machine learning (ML) and data science applications on advanced cyberinfrastructure and high-performance computing (HPC) systems.
&lt;/p&gt;</p>
<p>

This year’s CIML Summer Institute will involve introducing ML researchers, developers and educators to the techniques and methods needed to migrate their ML applications from smaller, locally run resources, such as laptops and workstations, to large-scale HPC systems, such as the SDSC Expanse supercomputer. Participants will have the opportunity to accelerate their learning process through highly interactive classes with hands-on tutorials on SDSC’s Expanse.
</p>
<p>

Although the institute will focus on 3 scientific domains (cardiology, bioinformatics, molecular dynamics), participants from all fields are welcome.
</p>
<p>
For more information see Institute event site:  [https://www.sdsc.edu/event_items/202206_cimlsi.html](https://www.sdsc.edu/event_items/202206_cimlsi.html).
</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="CIML" /><category term="NSF" /><category term="ML" /><category term="Best Practices" /><category term="Summer Institute" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SDSC's Cyberinfrastructure-Enabled Machine Learning Summer Institute The San Diego Supercomputer Center (SDSC) Cyberinfrastructure-Enabled Machine Learning (CIML) project is focused on teaching researchers and students the best-known practices for effectively running machine learning (ML) and data science applications on advanced cyberinfrastructure and high-performance computing (HPC) systems. &lt;/p&gt;]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SDSC CIML 2021 Summer Institute</title><link href="https://ciml.sdsc.edu//blog/2021/Summer-Inst/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SDSC CIML 2021 Summer Institute" /><published>2021-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ciml.sdsc.edu//blog/2021/Summer-Inst</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ciml.sdsc.edu//blog/2021/Summer-Inst/"><![CDATA[<h3>SDSC Cyberinfrastructure-Enabled Machine Learning Summer Institute</h3>
<p>
Tuesday, June 22, 2021 - Thursday, June 24, 2021<br />
<em>This event will be held remotely</em>
&lt;\p&gt;


<p>
The San Diego Supercomputer Center (SDSC) Cyberinfrastructure-Enabled Machine Learning (CIML) project is focused on teaching researchers and students the best-known practices for effectively running machine learning (ML) and data science applications on advanced cyberinfrastructure and high-performance computing (HPC) systems.
&lt;\p&gt;
<p>
This year’s CIML Summer Institute will involve introducing ML researchers, developers and educators to the techniques and methods needed to migrate their ML applications from smaller, locally run resources, such as laptops and workstations, to large-scale HPC systems, such as the SDSC Expanse supercomputer. Participants will have the opportunity to accelerate their learning process through highly interactive classes with hands-on tutorials on SDSC’s Expanse.
&lt;\p&gt;
Although the institute will focus on 3 scientific domains (cardiology, bioinformatics, molecular dynamics), participants from all fields are welcome.
&lt;\p&gt;
<p>
For more information see Institute event site:  [https://www.sdsc.edu/event_items/202106_cimlsi.html](https://www.sdsc.edu/event_items/202106_cimlsi.html).
&lt;\p&gt;
</p></p></p></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="CIML" /><category term="NSF" /><category term="ML" /><category term="Best Practices" /><category term="Summer Institute" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SDSC Cyberinfrastructure-Enabled Machine Learning Summer Institute Tuesday, June 22, 2021 - Thursday, June 24, 2021 This event will be held remotely &lt;\p&gt;]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SDSC HPC User Training to begin on January 22 2021</title><link href="https://ciml.sdsc.edu//blog/2020/SDSC-HPC-User-Training-to-begin-on-January-22-2021/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SDSC HPC User Training to begin on January 22 2021" /><published>2020-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ciml.sdsc.edu//blog/2020/SDSC-HPC-User-Training-to-begin-on-January-22-2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ciml.sdsc.edu//blog/2020/SDSC-HPC-User-Training-to-begin-on-January-22-2021/"><![CDATA[<p>
    The 2021 course is scheduled to be held in two sessions: Session #1: January 22, 2021 - March 12, 2021; Session #2: April 2, 2021 - May 7, 2021. Training sessions will be held on Fridays from 1:00pm to 3:00pm in the SDSC SynCenter (or the Auditorium, if needed). Registration and course details can be found <a href="https://na.eventscloud.com/website/21055/home/">here.</a>
</p>
<p>
    This High-Performance Computing (HPC) User Training series is open to all who are interested in advancing their knowledge and experience on HPC systems and concepts.  The program was originally developed in 2019 to support UCSD undergraduates interested in furthering their knowledge of HPC concepts and hands-on training, as well as, building a team interested in competing in the annual Student Cluster Competition held at the annual International Conference for High Performance Computing, Networking, Storage, and Analysis (SC). This program continues to focus efforts on building a team to compete in the annual SC Student Cluster Competition but also extends to any who are interested in attending.
</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="HPC User Training" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 2021 course is scheduled to be held in two sessions: Session #1: January 22, 2021 - March 12, 2021; Session #2: April 2, 2021 - May 7, 2021. Training sessions will be held on Fridays from 1:00pm to 3:00pm in the SDSC SynCenter (or the Auditorium, if needed). Registration and course details can be found here. This High-Performance Computing (HPC) User Training series is open to all who are interested in advancing their knowledge and experience on HPC systems and concepts. The program was originally developed in 2019 to support UCSD undergraduates interested in furthering their knowledge of HPC concepts and hands-on training, as well as, building a team interested in competing in the annual Student Cluster Competition held at the annual International Conference for High Performance Computing, Networking, Storage, and Analysis (SC). This program continues to focus efforts on building a team to compete in the annual SC Student Cluster Competition but also extends to any who are interested in attending.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NSF Award Announced for the CIML Project</title><link href="https://ciml.sdsc.edu//blog/2020/NSF-Awards-the-CIML-Project/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NSF Award Announced for the CIML Project" /><published>2020-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ciml.sdsc.edu//blog/2020/NSF-Awards-the-CIML-Project</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ciml.sdsc.edu//blog/2020/NSF-Awards-the-CIML-Project/"><![CDATA[<h3>NSF Award Announced for the CIML Project!</h3>
<h2>NSF Award Ah2stract #2017767</h2>
<p>
<em>CyberTraining: Implementation: Small: Developing a Best Practices Training Program in Cyberinfrastructure-Enabled Machine Learning Research</em>
</p>
<p>
See: <a href="https://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward?AWD_ID=2017767&amp;HistoricalAwards=false">https://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward?AWD_ID=2017767&amp;HistoricalAwards=false</a>
</p>
<p>
The Cyberinfrastructure-enabled Machine Learning (CIML) training system will use a “best practices” approach to develop a unique program targeted towards the NSF workforce who use machine learning (ML) and big data analytics methods for their domain specific applications or instructional material on large-scale NSF funded cyberinfrastructure. We will apply methods of Cyber Literacy and HPC Competencies to define a set of core ML and domain specific literacy areas as a function of the dimensions of learning ranging from a technological focus to a problem-solving focus or a focus on ML or computational science. Sources for the CIML system will be drawn from the work of HPC training, existing HPC researchers and users, collaborators, as well as new code and methods. CIMIL efforts will be focussed on 2 communities: (1) users who want to understand what technologies and skills they need to master in order to run a particular ML application, what systems to use, and suggested software libraries; and (2) trainers who need to know what topics to teach.
</p>
<p>

The outcome of our efforts will result in a community of machine learning and data analytics CI Users (CIUs) and Contributors (CICs) who actively contribute to the training material repository and incorporate the materials into their projects and courses. The results of our efforts support both goals of the solicitation by ensuring that the CI modules run on advanced CI tools and resources (goal #1: “Broadening Adoption of Advanced CI,”), and that core literacy and discipline-appropriate advanced skills in advanced CI will be integrated into curriculum/instructional material (goal #2: “Integration of CI Skills into Curriculum/Instructional Material Fabric”). As a result of our efforts, the CIML program will extend the scope of the ongoing education and training across the NSF research workforce by developing cyberinfrastructure-based materials that will utilize and contribute to training material developed for XSEDE training, higher education, and other programs, and will impact thousands of existing and new users, including students (undergrads/grads), postdocs, PIs, researchers, and educators, each with their own diverse backgrounds and application requirements. CIML training material will be available online, so the project has an unlimited potential to reach beyond the NSF cyber workforce and to impact other communities including hospital and medical treatment systems, transportation and electrical monitoring systems, stock and market monitoring systems, and disaster response systems.
</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="CIML" /><category term="NSF" /><category term="ML" /><category term="Best Practices" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[CyberTraining: Implementation: Small: Developing a Best Practices Training Program in Cyberinfrastructure-Enabled Machine Learning Research]]></summary></entry></feed>